<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Turner</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chris Turner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The best of both worlds (R and Python)</title>
      <link>/post/2015/07/23/the-best-of-both-worlds-r-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015/07/23/the-best-of-both-worlds-r-and-python/</guid>
      <description>#Blog
After developing an understanding of how to use R-studio in my Computational Biology course this semester, my peers and I had the opportunity of combining R with Python. Python is a well-known computing language, but can also be used effectively for data science purposes and computational biology.
In this post, I will show how Python code can actually be used inside an R script after installing some packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis by Joaquin E. Moreno (JEM5638)</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>Packages used:
library(tidyverse) library(fivethirtyeight) library(dplyr) library(pastecs) library(Hmisc) #Q0: Introduction and Data Sets
data2019 &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;Data2019.csv&amp;quot;, header = TRUE, quote = &amp;quot;\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;, stringsAsFactors = TRUE, strip.white = TRUE) data2018 &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;Data2018.csv&amp;quot;, header = TRUE, quote = &amp;quot;\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;, stringsAsFactors = TRUE, strip.white = TRUE) For the purpose of this project, I used two data sets obtained from Kaggle(link below) which included statistics about Men’s NCAA Basketball tournament. I have always been a huge fan of college basketball and thought it would be great practice analyzing team statistics while using the skills that I have learned in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>#0:Data Set
For the purpose of this project, I used an official dataset used on Medicare.gov for hospital quality comparison which showed hospital ratings. This data set was obtained from Kaggle.com and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid. This data set contained 8 different variables, including: Hospital Name (Categorical), State (Categorical), Zip Code (numerical), Hospital Type; Acute, Critical, or Children’s Hosp. (Categorical), Ownership of Hospital;Voluntary Non Profit, Proprietary, or Government Owned (Categorical), Emergency Services Available; Yes=1/No=2 (Binary Numerical), Hospital Rating; Scale of 1-5 (Numerical), and Average Amount of Nights Spent by Patients (Numerical).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
